JUAN CAMILO BUSTAMANTE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Bogotá Colombia

PHONE

+57 314 307 5254

EMAIL

juanc_bustamante_@hotmail.com

LINKS

adidas Locker Room

LANGUAGES

Spanish

• • • •

English

• • • • •

Italian

• • 0 0 0

PROFILE

Senior Software Engineer with 5 years of experience in front-end development teams for global product areas. I excel in translating product strategy to capabilities and solutions applying design thinking and engineering principles. My expertise includes web development, stakeholder management, design systems, and strategic vision. Notable achievements include leading the engineering team behind the launch of adidas Locker Room external site, generating €1M in revenue and acquiring 100K users in over 20 countries.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, adidas AG

Dec 2022 — Present

- Led of the front-end development team for the Global Team Sports product area, working alongside the product and design areas to design, refine and develop features in the Locker Room platform.
- Successfully launched the external Locker Room site, generating €1M in revenue and acquiring over 100K users.

Features developed include:

- · Implementation of adidas Design Language in Locker Room platform.
- · Content Management System (CMS) migration.
- · Bulk upload of team's roster information using CSV files.
- Refactor of Locker Room application using clean architecture principles: layers, adapters, services, components.

Software Engineer, Blackboard Inc.

Sep 2021 — Jul 2022

Associate Software Engineer, Blackboard Inc.

Oct 2019 — Sep 2021

Developed features and enhancements to the Learn Ultra LMS. Involvement in the design and definition process, working alongside Product Management and Design teams. The features developed include:

- · Journals.
- · Gradebook Advanced Filters.
- · Hide group sets from students.
- · Integration with Microsoft 365 using LTI.

Junior Developer, Integra IT S.A.S

Feb 2019 — May 2019

Design and develop software to support clinical trials and its data management, as well as solutions in the health care industry.

- Design and development of mobile app for aesthetic centers, which allows users to see the center's Instagram feed, schedule and pay the treatments offered. Developed in React Native and AWS.
- Functional testing and bug fixing in PFS II, which is a platform that gives support in data management of clinical trials. Developed in Java Play, JQuery and MySQL.

Support Engineer, SEIS Consulting S.A.S

Jan 2018 — Jun 2018

Support the development, documentation and testing of the platform Solar VORP of the National Hydrocarbons Agency (ANH), specially in the module "Economic Rights".

EDUCATION

Electronic Engineering, Universidad de los Andes

2012 - 2016

Systems and Computer Engineering, Universidad de los Andes

2013 — 2018

SKILLS

- TypeScript
- · React
- · Node.js
- · Amazon Web Services
- Java
- · SQL and Non-SQL Databases
- · Functional programming
- Design systems
- · Stakeholder management